Tibet
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Tibet
2.1.3.5
Marist College
  Box 1533
- Tibet, 2.1.3.5
  - Tibet: Accident [Lowell Thomas breaks hip when he falls off horse on leaving Tibet], 1949; 1 (Box 1533)
    - "O Lord Buddha, lighten our load!" chanted bearers of LT Sr's chair as they made the journey down. T-270, 1
    - Verso: "O Lord Buddha, lighten our load!" chanted bearers of LT Sr's chair as they made the journey down. T-270, 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas being carried in a chair], 2
  - Tibet: Accident [Lowell Thomas on crutches], 1949; 2 (Box 1533)
    - LOWELL THOMAS RETURNS FROM TIBET, Lowell Thomas, newscaster, waves a crutch as he leaves a Pan American World Airways plane at La Guardia Field, New York, Oct. 16, upon his return by air from a trip to Tibet. He was accompanied by his son, Lowell, Jr. (left). Thomas broke a thigh bone in a fall from a horse on a Tibetan mountain pass last summer. He said he believed Tibet, which has an army of 10,000 would accept outside help if attacked by Chinese Communists, 10/16/49, 1
    - Note: LOWELL THOMAS RETURNS FROM TIBET, Lowell Thomas, newscaster, waves a crutch as he leaves a Pan American World Airways plane at La Guardia Field, New York, Oct. 16, upon his return by air from a trip to Tibet. He was accompanied by his son, Lowell, Jr. (left). Thomas broke a thigh bone in a fall from a horse on a Tibetan mountain pass last summer. He said he believed Tibet, which has an army of 10,000 would accept outside help if attacked by Chinese Communists, 10/16/49, 2
    - Sunday Oct. 16, 1949; East Boston Airport, 3
    - Verso: Sunday Oct. 16, 1949; East Boston Airport, 3-verso
    - New York Bureau, THOMAS RETURNS FROM TIBET, NEW YORK: Lowell Thomas, explorer and radio commentator, is greeted by his father, Dr. Harry G. Thomas (right) as he and his son, Lowell Thomas, Jr., (left) arrive at La Guardia Field, Oct. 16. The Commentator was injured in a fall from his horse while riding in the Himalayas. He suffered a broken pelvis. From Karo Pass, 16, 700 feet above sea level, Thomas said he was carried on a litter to Gyantse, a six-day trip, and thence to the Indian border, a journey of some eight days. Thomas said the rulers of Tibet want to know if the U.S. will help them in the event of a Communist invasion. 10-16-49 (LG), 4
    - Note: New York Bureau, THOMAS RETURNS FROM TIBET, NEW YORK: Lowell Thomas, explorer and radio commentator, is greeted by his father, Dr. Harry G. Thomas (right) as he and his son, Lowell Thomas, Jr., (left) arrive at La Guardia Field, Oct. 16. The Commentator was injured in a fall from his horse while riding in the Himalayas. He suffered a broken pelvis. From Karo Pass, 16, 700 feet above sea level, Thomas said he was carried on a litter to Gyantse, a six-day trip, and thence to the Indian border, a journey of some eight days. Thomas said the rulers of Tibet want to know if the U.S. will help them in the event of a Communist invasion. 10-16-49 (LG), 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas Jr. being greeted by his father, Harry G. Thomas], 6
    - THOMAS LEAVES HOSPITAL, Lowell Thomas, noted CBS newscaster, today bade farewell to Assistant Director Phyllis M. Young (left) and supervisor Waveney Towey, as he left the Harkness Pavilion of the Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center, where he was operated on for a broken hip bone, suffered in a fall from a horse on his recent visit to the Dalai Lama in the Forbidden City of Lhasa, Tibet. He went from the hospital to his home in Pawling, N.Y., where he will complete his recovery, broadcasting from there daily on his CBS 6:45-7:00 PM, EST, news program, 7
    - Note: THOMAS LEAVES HOSPITAL, Lowell Thomas, noted CBS newscaster, today bade farewell to Assistant Director Phyllis M. Young (left) and supervisor Waveney Towey, as he left the Harkness Pavilion of the Columbia Presbyterian Medical Center, where he was operated on for a broken hip bone, suffered in a fall from a horse on his recent visit to the Dalai Lama in the Forbidden City of Lhasa, Tibet. He went from the hospital to his home in Pawling, N.Y., where he will complete his recovery, broadcasting from there daily on his CBS 6:45-7:00 PM, EST, news program, 8
    - [Lowell Thomas leaving the hospital where he was treated for a broken hip], 9
  - Tibet: Buildings, 1949; 3 (Box 1533)
    - Typical Tibetan home. Doorway to courtyard, T-37, 1
    - Verso: Typical Tibetan home. Doorway to courtyard, T-37, 1-verso
    - Lhasa For. [Foreign] Office, T-122, 2
    - Verso: Lhasa For. [Foreign] Office, T-122, 2-verso
    - Lhasa House-yaks in courtyard, T-121, 3
    - Verso: Lhasa House-yaks in courtyard, T-121, 3-verso
  - Tibet: Dalai Lama, 1949; 4 (Box 1533)
    - 15 yr. old Dalai Lama on his throne in Lhasa, 1949, 1
    - Note: 15 yr. old Dalai Lama on his throne in Lhasa, 1949, 2
    - (photographed in 1949) A formal portrait of His Holiness. Beside the throne, are members of his household; behind the pillar, the Lord Chamberlain (Property of Lowell Thomas, Jr.) p. 205, 3
    - Verso: (photographed in 1949) A formal portrait of His Holiness. Beside the throne, are members of his household; behind the pillar, the Lord Chamberlain (Property of Lowell Thomas, Jr.) p. 205, 3-verso
    - Wearing the gold peaked cap that is his crown, the Dalai Lama receives and blesses pilgrims. With him, the Lord Chamberlain; D.L. on throne - unsmiling; Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr., 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, 4
    - Verso: Wearing the gold peaked cap that is his crown, the Dalai Lama receives and blesses pilgrims. With him, the Lord Chamberlain; D.L. on throne - unsmiling; Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr., 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, 4-verso
    - Dalai Lama on his throne, 5
    - Verso: Dalai Lama on his throne, 5-verso
    - (photographed in 1949) The Dalai Lama, center (fourth from left) (at left Lowell Thomas, Sr.) (Property of Lowell Thomas, Jr.) 50 Rockefeller Plaza N.Y. 20, p. 209, T-233, 6
    - Verso: (photographed in 1949) The Dalai Lama, center (fourth from left) (at left Lowell Thomas, Sr.) (Property of Lowell Thomas, Jr.) 50 Rockefeller Plaza N.Y. 20, p. 209, T-233, 6-verso
    - The Dalai Lama, 4th from Lowell Thomas, Sr. on left, T-233, p. 209, 7
    - Verso: The Dalai Lama, 4th from Lowell Thomas, Sr. on left, T-233, p. 209, 7-verso
    - D.L. and advisors standing in aud. hall. L.T. on left, T-234, 8
    - Verso: D.L. and advisors standing in aud. hall. L.T. on left, T-234, 8-verso
    - Same of D.L. in aud. hall, med. shot, 9
    - Verso: Same of D.L. in aud. hall, med. shot, 9-verso
    - D.L.'s advisors and L.T., T-237, 10
    - Verso: D.L.'s advisors and L.T., T-237, 10-verso
    - D.L.'s advisors and L.T., T-237, 11
    - L.T. photographing Dalai Lama in Lhasa; Return to: Miss Mary Davis, Lowell Thomas, 50 Rockefeller Plaza, New York City, NY, Room 1536; Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-231, 12
    - Verso: L.T. photographing Dalai Lama in Lhasa; Return to: Miss Mary Davis, Lowell Thomas, 50 Rockefeller Plaza, New York City, NY, Room 1536; Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-231, 12-verso
    - Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 13
    - Verso: Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 13-verso
    - Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 14
    - Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 15
    - Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 16
    - Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 17
    - Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 18
    - Flanked by chrysanthemums and other flowers, the Dalai Lama poses for us on an outdoor throne. He is worshipped as the reincarnation of Chenrezi [Chenrezig], God of Mercy. On the right stands Regent Tokra, who rules until His Holiness comes of age. Credit Lowell Thomas, Jr. 50 Rockefeller Plaza, N.Y. 20, T-232, 19
    - Lhasa - Panchen Lama, T-248, 20
    - Verso: Lhasa - Panchen Lama, T-248, 20-verso
    - Lhasa - Panchen Lama, T-248, 21
    - [Lowell Thomas with Panchen Lama], 22
    - [Lowell Thomas with Panchen Lama], 23
    - [Lowell Thomas, Jr. with Panchen Lama], 24
    - [Lowell Thomas, Jr. with Panchen Lama], 25
    - [Lowell Thomas, Jr. with Panchen Lama], 26
    - [Lowell Thomas, Jr. with Panchen Lama], 27
    - [The Dalai Lama on his throne in Lhasa, 15 years old], 28
    - [15-year-old Dalai Lama on his throne in Lhasa, 1949], 29
    - [The Panchen Lama], 30
  - Tibet: Dalai Lama's family, 1949; 5 (Box 1533)
    - To: Mr. Lowell Thomas with sincere best wishes, Sonam Wangmo Tenduf La; The afternoon this picture was taken, it was exceedingly windy, and we were trying to keep out [sic] feet on earth! 1. The Dalai Lama's mother; 2. My father, Mr. C. Tenduf La; 3. My mother, Mrs. P.L. Tenduf La; 4. Mary Taring who acted as secretary to the Dalai Lama's family; 5. Tshering Doma, the Dalai Lama's elder sister; 6. The Dalai Lama's younger sister; 7. The Dalai Lama's neice; I am standing on the extreme left, 1
    - Verso: To: Mr. Lowell Thomas with sincere best wishes, Sonam Wangmo Tenduf La; The afternoon this picture was taken, it was exceedingly windy, and we were trying to keep out [sic] feet on earth! 1. The Dalai Lama's mother; 2. My father, Mr. C. Tenduf La; 3. My mother, Mrs. P.L. Tenduf La; 4. Mary Taring who acted as secretary to the Dalai Lama's family; 5. Tshering Doma, the Dalai Lama's elder sister; 6. The Dalai Lama's younger sister; 7. The Dalai Lama's neice; I am standing on the extreme left, 1-verso
    - L.T. with parents + family; Dalai Lama in Lhasa, 2
    - Verso: L.T. with parents + family; Dalai Lama in Lhasa, 2-verso
    - Note: from: Columbia Broadcasting System, INC. 485 Madison Avenue, New York 22, N.Y., Plaza I-2345; 1949: A Visit to Tibet A memorable moment in journalism took place in 1949 when CBS News Correspondent Lowell Thomas and his son penetrated the Himalayas and reached Lhasa, the forbidden city of Tibet, for an exclusive interview with the Dalai Lama. In this photo Mr. Thomas is seen with the family of the Dalai Lama with the Potala, the Dalai Lama's palace, rising in the background., 3
    - [Lowell Thomas with the family of the Dalai Lama], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas with the Dalai Lama's family], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas with the Dalai Lama's family], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas with the Dalai Lama's family], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas with the Dalai Lama's family], 8
    - D.L.'s [Dalai Lama's] mother, brother, two nieces and a nephew and L.T.; D.L.'s mother, big bro, small brother, 2 nieces + L.T. closeup, 9
    - Verso: D.L.'s [Dalai Lama's] mother, brother, two nieces and a nephew and L.T.; D.L.'s mother, big bro, small brother, 2 nieces + L.T. closeup, 9-verso
  - Tibet: En route to Tibet, 1949; 6 (Box 1533)
    - Stoney [sic] road leaving Chumbi Valley; T-1, 1
    - Verso: Stoney [sic] road leaving Chumbi Valley; T-1, 1-verso
    - Chumbi Valley, clouds and trail; T-4, 2
    - Verso: Chumbi Valley, clouds and trail; T-4, 2-verso
    - Caravan descending-green valley; T-5, 3
    - Verso: Caravan descending-green valley; T-5, 3-verso
    - Trail along the Ammo near Yatung; T-7, 4
    - Verso:Trail along the Ammo near Yatung; T-7, 4-verso
    - Two traders; T-11, 5
    - Verso: Two traders; T-11, 5-verso
    - Shrine to propitiate demons near Phari; T-14, 6
    - Verso: Shrine to propitiate demons near Phari; T-14, 6-verso
    - Loading caravan, at village on high plateau between Phari and Lhasa; T-20, 7
    - Verso: Loading caravan, at village on high plateau between Phari and Lhasa; T-20, 7-verso
    - Caravan mule with a noble's personal flag, bells, and usual burden; T-27, 8
    - Verso: Caravan mule with a noble's personal flag, bells, and usual burden; T-27, 8-verso
    - T-70 [Man in Tibet], 9
    - Verso: T-70 [Man in Tibet], 9-verso
    - Yak grazing; T 74, 10
    - Verso: Yak grazing; T 74, 10-verso
    - Head of yaks, boy and tent; T-78, 11
    - Verso: Head of yaks, boy and tent; T-78, 11-verso
    - Yaks crossing lofty Nyapso La; T-79, 12
    - Verso: Yaks crossing lofty Nyapso La; T-79, 12-verso
    - 1 yak team plowing; T-82, 13
    - Verso: 1 yak team plowing; T-82, 13-verso
    - Bearers in Kyi Chu River; T-84, 14
    - Verso: Bearers in Kyi Chu River; T-84, 14-verso
    - Bearer in water - with CBS case - rear; T-84, 15
    - Verso: Bearer in water - with CBS case - rear; T-84, 15-verso
    - Caravan entering river; T-86, 16
    - Verso: Caravan entering river; T-86, 16-verso
    - LT on white mule-looking away; near Mt Chomo Lhari "Queen of the Snow" famous white mtn [mountain]; T-87, 17
    - Verso: LT on white mule-looking away; near Mt Chomo Lhari "Queen of the Snow" famous white mtn [mountain]; T-87, 17-verso
    - Caravan on banks of Kyi Chu; T-88, 18
    - Verso: Caravan on banks of Kyi Chu; T-88, 18-verso
    - White horse clamboring [sic] up rocks; T-89, 19
    - Verso: White horse clamboring [sic] up rocks; T-89, 19-verso
    - Same-front; T-90 [bearer in water with CBS case on back], 20
    - Verso: Same-front; T-90 [bearer in water with CBS case on back], 20-verso
    - Caravan in stream; T-91, 21
    - Verso: Caravan in stream; T-91, 21-verso
    - Bearer with CBS case, fording the Kyi Chu River, tributary of the Brahmaputra; Where the caravan route had disappeared; T-94, 22
    - Verso: Bearer with CBS case, fording the Kyi Chu River, tributary of the Brahmaputra; Where the caravan route had disappeared; T-94, 22-verso
    - Where the caravan route had dissapeared, 23
    - Verso: Where the caravan route had dissapeared, 23-verso
    - T-94 [Where the caravan route disappeared], 24
    - Verso: T-94 [Where the caravan route disappeared], 24-verso
    - T-94 [Where the caravan route disappeared], 25
    - Verso: T-94 [Where the caravan route disappeared], 25-verso
    - T-94 [Where the caravan route disappeared], 26
    - Verso: T-94 [Where the caravan route disappeared], 26-verso
    - Fording river around cliff - long shot; T-97, 27
    - Verso: Fording river around cliff - long shot; T-97, 27-verso
    - Due to heavy August rains we were obliged to ford many rivers, tributaries of the Brahmaputra. Fording the Kyi Chu-a tributary of the Brahmaputra - on the way to Lhasa; T-98, 28
    - Verso: Due to heavy August rains we were obliged to ford many rivers, tributaries of the Brahmaputra. Fording the Kyi Chu-a tributary of the Brahmaputra - on the way to Lhasa; T-98, 28-verso
    - Due to heavy August rains we were obliged to ford many rivers, tributaries of the Brahmaputra. Fording the Kyi Chu-a tributary of the Brahmaputra - on the way to Lhasa; T-98, 29
  - Tibet: En route to Tibet, 1949; 7 (Box 1533)
    - Grinning boatman-CBS-on Brahmaputra, highest navigable river in world; T-103, 1
    - Verso: Grinning boatman-CBS-on Brahmaputra, highest navigable river in world; T-103, 1-verso
    - T-108 [boatman, Lowell Thomas seated at right], 2
    - Verso: T-108 [boatman, Lowell Thomas seated at right], 2-verso
    - Gambling beside water; T-141, 3
    - Verso: Gambling beside water; T-141, 3-verso
    - Chomolari - yaks; T-274, 4
    - Verso: Chomolari - yaks; T-274, 4-verso
    - T-277B [Lowell Thomas interviewing Harishwar Dayal, Lowell Thomas, Jr. with back to camera], 5
    - Verso: T-277B, 5-verso
    - Broadcasting from the Himalyas, 6
    - Verso: Broadcasting from the Himalyas, 6-verso
    - Harishwar Dayal and L.T., Gangtok, Sikkim; T-277C, 7
    - Verso: Harishwar Dayal and L.T., Gangtok, Sikkim; T-277C, 7-verso
    - T-277E [Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. preparing to broadcast en route to Tibet], 8
    - Verso: T-277E [Lowell Thomas and Lowell Thomas, Jr. preparing to broadcast en route to Tibet], 8-verso
    - T-277F [Lowell Thomas talking to a Tibetan man], 9
    - Verso: T-277F [Lowell Thomas talking to a Tibetan man], 9-verso
    - Lashing CBS case on pack animal; T-278, 10
    - Verso: Lashing CBS case on pack animal; T-278, 10-verso
    - Nathu La, at fourteen thousand five hundred feet, where you throw stones at the Devil before crossing into Tibet. Nathu La, the high Himalayan pass between Sikkim and Tibet. Before crossing you throw stones at the Devil, 11
    - Verso: Nathu La, at fourteen thousand five hundred feet, where you throw stones at the Devil before crossing into Tibet. Nathu La, the high Himalayan pass between Sikkim and Tibet. Before crossing you throw stones at the Devil, 11-verso
    - L.T. and CBS equipment at Karo La, 17,000 ft., highest pass on caravan route to Lhasa, 12
    - Verso: L.T. and CBS equipment at Karo La, 17,000 ft., highest pass on caravan route to Lhasa, 12-verso
    - L.T.-CBS-atop Karo La (17,000 ft.) highest pass en route Lhasa; T-281, 13
    - Verso: L.T.-CBS-atop Karo La (17,000 ft.) highest pass en route Lhasa; T-281, 13-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas and CBS equipment at Karo La, 17,000 feet, highest pass on caravan route to Lhasa], 14
    - T-283A [Lowell Thomas showing something to a Tibetan man], 15
    - Verso: T-283A [Lowell Thomas showing something to a Tibetan man], 15-verso
    - Mr. Dayal helping describe the caravan loading at Gangtok. Also a Mahratta captain, 16
    - Verso: Mr. Dayal helping describe the caravan loading at Gangtok. Also a Mahratta captain, 16-verso
    - Mr. Dayal helping describe the caravan loading at Gangtok. Also a Mahratta captain, 17
    - Verso: T-283B [Mr. Dayal helping describe the caravan loading at Gangtok], 17-verso
    - Mr. Dayal helping describe the caravan loading at Gangtok. Also a Mahratta captain, 18
    - On the way to Lhasa, 19
    - Verso: On the way to Lhasa, 19-verso
    - Namgyal, 20
    - Verso: Namgyal, 20-verso
    - L.T. Jr. and Sr., just over Nathu La; T-285, 21
    - Verso: L.T. Jr. and Sr., just over Nathu La; T-285, 21-verso
    - Same - 1st stop in Tibet; T-286, 22
    - Verso: Same - 1st stop in Tibet; T-286, 22-verso
    - On the trail. 6 animals; T-300, 23
    - Verso: On the trail. 6 animals; T-300, 23-verso
    - Thru the mist, scaling the southern slope of the Himalayas; T-303, 24
    - Verso: Thru the mist, scaling the southern slope of the Himalayas; T-303, 24-verso
    - More climbing into the clouds - from rear; T-305, 25
    - Verso: More climbing into the clouds - from rear; T-305, 25-verso
    - Climbing towards Nathu La; T-307, 26
    - Verso: Climbing towards Nathu La; T-307, 26-verso
    - Trail, cloud, L.T. on mule. T-308, 27
    - Verso: Trail, cloud, L.T. on mule. T-308, 27-verso
    - Native, striding-and 1 bearer; T-309, 28
    - Verso: Native, striding-and 1 bearer; T-309, 28-verso
    - Resting beside trail in Sikkim; T-310, 29
    - Verso: Resting beside trail in Sikkim; T-310, 29-verso
    - Caravan - 10 animals. Rider at each end; T-312, 30
    - Verso: Caravan - 10 animals. Rider at each end; T-312, 30-verso
    - Within few yards of Nathu La in mist; T-315, 31
    - Verso: Within few yards of Nathu La in mist; T-315, 31-verso
    - L.T. on white horse, 32
    - Verso: L.T. on white horse, 32-verso
  - Tibet: En route to Tibet, 1949; 8 (Box 1533)
    - [Climbing through the mist, in Sikkim, Tibet, at 8,000 feet to Lhasa], 1
    - Climbing thru the mist, in Sikkim at 8,000 feet, on the way to Lhasa, 2
    - Verso: Climbing thru the mist, in Sikkim at 8,000 feet, on the way to Lhasa, 2-verso
    - Caravan moving along left bank of Kyi Chu River, 3
    - Verso: Caravan moving along left bank of Kyi Chu River, 3-verso
    - [Far-off mountains in Tibet], 4
    - [Caravan on the way to Lhasa], 5
    - [Herd of oxen in Tibet], 6
    - [Herd of oxen at the base of Tibetan mountains], 7
    - [Herd of oxen at the base of Tibetan mountains], 8
    - [Herd of oxen in Tibet], 9
    - [Caravan on the way to Lhasa], 10
    - [Group of people and oxen in Tibet], 11
    - [Tibetan tents], 12
    - [Mother and child outside a tent in Tibet], 13
    - [Mother and child outside a tent in Tibet], 14
    - [Group of Tibetan people standing outside a tent], 15
    - [Town at the base of a mountain in Tibet], 16
    - [Mountain road in Tibet], 17
    - [Tibetan man in the fields], 18
  - Tibet: Lhasa shops, 1949; 9 (Box 1533)
    - Lhasa shop - abacus; T 132, 1
    - Verso: Lhasa shop - abacus; T 132, 1-verso
    - L.T. standing at counter in Lhasa shop, 2
    - Verso: L.T. standing at counter in Lhasa shop, 2-verso
    - Dorje-street shop, 3
    - Verso: Dorje-street shop, 3-verso
    - Street shop under a canopy; T-134, 4
    - Verso: Street shop under a canopy; T-134, 4-verso
    - Lhasa street shop. Strings of yak cheese; T-126, 5
    - Verso: Lhasa street shop. Strings of yak cheese; T-126, 5-verso
  - Tibet: Military, 1949; 10 (Box 1533)
    - Army drum corps, 1
    - Verso: Army drum corps, 1-verso
    - [Tibetan army], 2
    - [Tibetan army], 3
    - [Tibetan army officer], 4
  - Tibet: Monks, 1949; 11 (Box 1533)
    - (Caption:) The Lord Chamberlain, Chi-Kyap Kempo - the most important member of the Dalai Lama's household. Word has come of his passing away during the winter of 1949-50; T-239, 1
    - Verso: (Caption:) The Lord Chamberlain, Chi-Kyap Kempo - the most important member of the Dalai Lama's household. Word has come of his passing away during the winter of 1949-50; T-239, 1-verso
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. and the top monk advisors to the Dalai Lama [including the Lord Chamberlain, Chi-Kyap Kempo, center]; T-238, 2
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas, Jr. and the top monk advisors to the Dalai Lama [including the Lord Chamberlain, Chi-Kyap Kempo, center]; T-238, 2-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. and the top monk advisors to the Dalai Lama], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. and the top monk advisors to the Dalai Lama], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. and the top monk advisors to the Dalai Lama], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and the top monk advisors to the Dalai Lama, including the Lord Chamberlain, Chi-Kyap Kempo, center], 6
    - Verso: T-237, 6-verso
    - L.T. and monk, 7
    - Verso: L.T. and monk, 7-verso
    - A monastery courtyard; T-208, 8
    - Verso: A monastery courtyard; T-208, 8-verso
    - A Golden roof on cathedral at Lhasa; T 219, 9
    - Verso: A Golden roof on cathedral at Lhasa; T 219, 9-verso